AFT Local 2 Records 5279
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
AFT Local 2 Records
1918-1957
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
American Federation of Teachers (AFT)
AFT Local 2
5279
24.5 cubic feet
21.5 linear ft.
Records.
Office files of the Teachers Guild, Local #2 of the American Federation of Teachers.
3338483
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, February 07, 2003
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, April 05, 2016
Biographical / Historical
The Teacher's Union, Local 5, was organized in 1916 as an affiliate of the American Federation of Teachers, (AF of L) by Henry R. Linville, Abraham Lefkowitz and a few other pioneering teachers in New York City.
Perhaps the most significant contribution of the T.U. during those early years was its fight on behalf of civil liberties, an area in which it would later become a formidable combatant. Its principal target was the repeal of the Lusk laws, statutes which allowed for the revocation of a teacher's license "if he is not of good moral character -- or if by act or utterance he shows that he will not support the constitution of the State or of the United States of America."
During the 1920's the T.U. continued its fight for increased salaries commensurate with the higher cost of living, reduced classroom size, tenure for teachers, improvements in the pension system, and increased state aid education. Unfortunately, the results rarely met the organization's expectations.
About 1925, organized political factions began appearing within the T.U.'s ranks. After 1929, two such groups were dominant in their opposition to the majority organization: the "Rank and File" group which represented the official Communist Party of America, and the "Progressive" group which represented a faction within the Communist movement opposed to the official party.
The leadership of Local 5 soon realized that it was helpless in the factional battle that ensued because of an overly liberal constitution, which had been designed to insure the rights of all minority groups whatever their objectives. In an attempt to rid its house of revolutionary elements, on October 27, 1932, at a large membership meeting, a Committee of Five was selected to try five members of the Rank and File group and one member of the Progressive group on the charge of disruptive conduct.
John Dewey, chairman, delivered the unanimous report of the Committee on April 29, 1933 before a Membership meeting of approximately 800. As was anticipated, the Committee reported that the primary cause of the intolerable strike within the Teachers' Union was due to the existence and activity of the two Communist organized factions. With the support of both the Executive Board and the Delegate Assembly, the local petitioned the national office to investigate the local and sought to have the local's old charter revoked so that a new local might be formed without the Communist element.
In May 1935, the national office sent an investigating committee composed of its president, secretary-treasurer and its Washington representative. The Committee's finding was that the local union "was 'helpless' and 'completely at the mercy of a small obstructionist group in the local', and that the obstructionist's group was itself 'not free to formulate its own policies but was subject to a political force which is itself fundamentally opposed to basic principles for which the union attends.'"
Despite this report of the investigating committee, a request by the administration of the Teachers Union to reorganize the local was turned down at the A.F.T. National Convention in August 1935 by a vote of 100 to 79. As a result, October 1, 1935, Henry R. Linville and Abraham Lefkowitz led eight hundred dissatisfied members out of the Teachers Union and into the newly formed independent Teachers Guild. Also among the seceding members were all the officers (with the exception of one) and a majority of the Executive Board.
In 1936, the Executive Council of the American Federation of Labor, as a result of testimony taken before a sub-committee in Washington, recommended to the American Federation of Teachers that it revoke the charter issued to Teachers Union Local 5. The A.F.T., however, did not see fit to abide by this recommendation.
On March 15, 1938 the Greater New York Central Trades and Labor Council suspended the Teachers Union from membership in its organization. Also in March, Teachers Union, Local 5 was expelled from the Joint Committee of Teachers Organizations of New York City.
Again in 1941, the subject of Local 5's charter revocation came up before the American Federation of teachers. However, this time the Executive Council recommended (with one dissenting vote) revocation and their action was overwhelmingly endorsed by the delegates at the Conventions in August 1941, at Detroit. After having its charter revoked, the Teachers Unions continued as Local 555 of the United Public Workers of the Congress of Industrial Organizations. The C.I.O. in February 1950 expelled the United Public Workers due to its alleged Communist domination. The Teachers Union, however, continued its association with the U.P.W. until it withdrew in February 1952.
Finally, in 1964, at the suggestion of Rose Russell, one of the T.U.'s guiding lights, the annual convention dissolved the T.U. with the recommendation that its members unite with the other forces in the New York City Teacher's Movement. On June 20, prior to the 1941 Convention, the Teachers Guild accepted the offer of a charter and was reunited with the American Federation of Teachers. Although it retained its name of the Teachers Guild, it was now designated Local 2, AFT.
The Teachers Guild during this period increased in both size and strength. In March, 1960, the Teachers Guild merged with the CATU (Committee of Action Through Unity) to form the United Federation of Teachers. Under the auspices of the New York City Labor Department and empowered by the Board of Education, a representation election was scheduled and held on December 15, 1961. The results were overwhelmingly in favor of the U.F.T. (Local 2, AFT) and so the following August the Board of Education and the U.F.T. entered into their first collective bargaining relationship.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5015: Teachers Union of the City of New York Records 5019: AFT Executive Council Transcript of Hearing of Local 5 5020: AFT Executive Council Transcript of Hearing of Local 537 5279: AFT Local 2 Records 5417 mf: AFT Local 2 Scrapbook on Microfilm 5845: AFT Local 616 (Rochester, NY) Federation of Classroom Teachers Records
American Federation of Labor; Americans for Democratic Action; Brookwood Labor College; Communist Party of the United States of America; National Education Association of the United States; New York (N.Y.). Board of Education.; New York Teachers Guild; Teachers Guild; United Nations; Austin, Warren Robinson; Count, George; Dewey, John, 1859-1952.; Dewey, Thomas E. (Thomas Edmund), 1902-1971.; Eaton, Charles Aubrey; Green, William, 1872-1952; Hillman, Sidney, 1887-1946; La Guardia, Fiorello H. (Fiorello Henry), 1882-1947; Lefkowitz, Abraham; Lie, Trygvi; Linville, Henry; Mooney, Thomas J., 1882-1942; O'Dwyer, William, 1890-1964; Perkins, Frances, 1882-1965; Russell, Bertrand, 1872-1970; Truman, Harry S., 1884-1972; Vandenburg, Arthur Hendrick
3338483
- Report of the Spirit - (Factionalism) (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Executive Board resigns (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Progressive Group - Factionalism pre-1935 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Other Local unions comments on the Split (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Controversy in 1935 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Most essential documents in the local #5 history (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Split and reorganization (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Material re: Split (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Split: Clippings, Trail Reports, etc. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Factionalism, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Clippings on the Split (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Split - preservation of local #5 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Committee to save AFT, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Minutes of Local #5, AFT, 1925-1935 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Committee of 25 - For union defense (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Committee of 100 - For union defense (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Statement before AFT Executive Board on Local #2 factionalism (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Linville, CCNY attack on (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Defense of union (Box 1, Folder 19)
- CIO organization of teachers (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Guild constitution and bylaws (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Folder on history of Local #5 - Local #2 relationship (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Membership applications (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Membership campaign material (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Membership committee - Henry Hillson, Chairman (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Membership list of Guild, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Membership resignations, deaths, expelled book (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Membership resignations, 1947-1948 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- The Teachers Union: A Social Study, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Guild: Union Attmepts at Unity, 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Local #5 New: Re: Revocation of charter (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Material for Local #5 ouster, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Organizing Committee (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Organizing propaganda, Guild - Folder #1 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Organizing propaganda, Guild - Folder #2 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Organizing propaganda, Guild - Folder #3 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Policy and bylaws (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Provisional committee, 1941 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Songs and the guild (and other) (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Membership drive, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Membership resignation, 1948-1949 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Communists and Left Wingers in Local #5 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Communism and socialism (Box 2, Folder 13)
- The Communist Teachers Issue - Folder #2 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Communist tactics in a trade union HR Linville (Box 2, Folder 15)
- The Communist Teachers Issue - Folder #1 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Pre and post trial correspondence, 1932-1933 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- The Communist Teachers Issue - Folder #3 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- McCarthy censure file (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Congressional investigation - Communism, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Daily Work clippings on the union split (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Communism - various news articles and correspondence (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Independent group in the teachers union (Trotskyites) (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Feinberg questionnaire (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Feinberg subversive folder (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Left-Wing material (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Election of officers, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Election of officers, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  Scope and Contents
  including Executive Board
- Elections - officers and Executive Board, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Guild elections, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Elections, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Elections, 1953-1954 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Ballot results, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Elections, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Form letters, 1938-1940 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Minutes, nominations, etc., 1947-1948 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Officers meetings -agendae, 1947-1948 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Officers meetings - agendae, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Executive Board - Officers correspondence, meetings, etc., 1948-1952 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Officers meeting agendae, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Minutes, notices of meetings, etc., 1941 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Rally letters, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Mimeograph, letters, etc. (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Souvenir Journal, 1954-1956 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Meeting reports, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Mrs. Rebecca Simonson - President of Guild (Box 3, Folder 20)
  Resume, correspondence, etc.
- Spring Conference, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Spring Conference, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Spring Conference, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Spring Conference, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Spring Conference, 1952-1953 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Spring Conference, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Spring Conference, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- October Conference - Printed programs, 1935-1940 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Fall Conference, 1948-1950 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- Conference Board - Notice of meetings, 1938-1939 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Conference Board, 1944-1946 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Legislation, 1952-1954 (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Legislation, 1954-1955 (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Legislative Briefs, 1948-1949 (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Legislative Bulletins, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Legislative Bulletins and Briefs, 1948-1949 (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Legislative Bulletins and Briefs, 1950-1951 (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Legislative Bulletins and Briefs, 1951-1952 (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Legislative Bulletins and Briefs, 1953-1954 (Box 3, Folder 39)
- Legislative Material, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 40)
- Legislative Committee, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Legislative Committee, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Maloff, Rubin - Assistant Legislative Representative (Box 4, Folder 3)
  Correspondence, etc
- Budget, Taxes and finances for education, 1937-1942 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Statements on budgets, finances, 1938-1941 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Educational budget material, 1943-1944 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Legislation and education budget, 1945-1946 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Board of Education budget hearings (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Adult elementary school teachers chapter (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Clerks chapter (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Trade teachers group (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Westinghouse teachers guild (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Dieticians chapter (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Teachers Guild Association Materials, 1938-1940 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Teachers Guild Association Materials, 1935-1938 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Teachers Guild Association Materials, 1939-1941 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Teachers Guild Association Materials, 1943-1945 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Teachers Guild Association Materials, 1946-1947 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Legislative Program, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  and prior
- Legislative Program, 1939 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  Dr. Lefkowitz
- Legislative Program, 1939-1941 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Legislative Program, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Legislative Program, 1946-1947 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Legislative Program, 1947-1948 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Associated Teachers Interest Committees (Box 4, Folder 25)
- College Affairs Committee (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Code of Conduct - Ethics (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Code of Ethic Committee (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Coordinating Committee (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Democratic Human Relations Committee (AFT) (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Democratization of School Administration Committee (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Educational Policies Committee (Wartime Curriculum) (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Educational Policies Committee [folder 1 of 3], 1954 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Educational Policies Committee [folder 2 of 3], 1954 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Educational Policies Committee [folder 3 of 3], 1954 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Educational TV Committee (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Elementary School Committee (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Emergency Committee (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Equality in Education Committee (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Expansion Fund Committee (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Joint Committee of Teachers Organization (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Guild Committee (General List of) (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Jewish Labor Committee (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Junior High School Committee (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Juvenile Delinquency Committee (Box 5, Folder 19)
- High School Affairs Committee (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Labor and Community Relations Committee (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Labor Committee on Schools (Box 5, Folder 22)
- Laboratory Assistants Committee (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Librarians Committee [fodler 1 of 2] (Box 5, Folder 24)
- Librarian's Committee [folder 2 of 2] (Box 5, Folder 25)
- Library Committee (May Dunn) (Box 5, Folder 26)
- Membership Committee (correspondence) (Box 5, Folder 27)
- Mental Hygiene Committee (Box 5, Folder 28)
- Pension Committee (Box 6, Folder 1a)
  3 folders
- Pension Committee (Box 6, Folder 1b)
- Pension Committee (Box 6, Folder 1c)
- Pension Committee - Mr. Louis Goldman (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Problem Areas Committee, 1942 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  Joint TG & TGA
- Professional Problems, Advisory Committee on (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Reorganization Committee (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Resolution Committee (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Sex Education Committee (Box 6, Folder 7)
- Shower Attendants Committee (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Social Committee, 1947-1948 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Slow-Learner Committee (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Supervision, Report of Committee on (Box 6, Folder 11)
  included is a 192 page report titled: "Supervision in the Elementary Schools"
- Taxation and Finance Committee (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Teachers Interest Committee (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Veterans Committee (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Vocational Committee - Lawsuit (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Salary Campaign material, 1938-1941 (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Salary data clippings, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Salary fight, 1946 (Box 6, Folder 18)
- Salary Campaign, 1948-1949 (Box 6, Folder 19)
- Salary Campaign, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 20)
- Salary Campaign, 1949-1950 (Box 6, Folder 21)
- Salary Campaign - forms, releases, etc., 1949-1950 (Box 6, Folder 22)
- Salary Campaign - correspondence -, 1950-1951 (Box 6, Folder 23)
- Salary Strategy Committee - Etta Greenberg (Chairman), 1950-1951 (Box 6, Folder 24)
- Salary Campaign - Coaches Fund (Box 6, Folder 25)
- Academic Freedom Committee - Current Folder (Box 6, Folder 26)
- Academic Freedom Committee - Documents of Committee (Box 6, Folder 27)
- Salary Campaign, 1951-1952 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Salary Campaign, 1952-1953 (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Salary Campaign, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Salary Committee - (forms, releases, etc.) (Box 7, Folder 4)
- Advisory Committee on Teachers Salaries (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Meyer Committee on Teachers Salaries (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Board of Education: Salary Schedules (Box 7, Folder 7)
- Report on teachers Salaries, 1947 (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Campaign for single salary (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Barnett, Sidney - Academic Freedom Committee Chairman (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Re: Hammond - Morgan Law (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Loyalty oath material (Box 7, Folder 12a)
  2 large folders
- Loyalty oath material (Box 7, Folder 12b)
- Membership Material and dismissal cases (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Academic Freedom Committee Minutes and agenda of meetings (Box 7, Folder 14)
- National Academic Freedom Committee (Box 7, Folder 15)
- National Academic Freedom Committee, AFT (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Academic Freedom Committee - other organizations (Box 7, Folder 17)
- Principles of Academic Freedom (Box 7, Folder 18)
- Re: Rapp-Coudert Investigation - clippings, 1941 (Box 7, Folder 19a)
  2 folders
- Re: Rapp-Coudert Investigation - clippings, 1941 (Box 7, Folder 19b)
- Recommendations and reports for a better system vol. #1 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Recommendations and reports for a better system vol. #1 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Teachers Examination Committee - correspondence, 1948-1955 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Applications for teaching license (Box 8, Folder 4)
- General petition and resolutions (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Brameld, Theodore - case (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Champlain College (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Hartmann, George - case (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Gioia, Andrew O. - case (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Dushane, Eleanor - case (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Gutride, Minnie - case (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Civil and academic rights (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Mandell, Benjamin - case (Re: recall, etc.) (Box 8, Folder 13)
- Lenz, Harold - case (Box 8, Folder 14)
- Problems and grievances, 1934-1935 (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Rubin, Isadore - case (Box 8, Folder 16)
- Lanzer, Irving R. - case (Swadesh - City College) (Box 8, Folder 17)
- Klein, Henry - case (Box 8, Folder 18)
- Heitner, Louis - grievance case (Box 8, Folder 19)
- Weyler, David - case (Box 8, Folder 20)
- Predergast, Laurence E. - case (Box 8, Folder 21)
- Quinn, May - case, 1946 (Box 8, Folder 22)
- Grievances, 1935-1936 (Box 8, Folder 23)
- Grievances, 1937 (Box 8, Folder 24)
- Problem of overcrowded classrooms, etc. (Box 8, Folder 25)
- Miscellaneous problems: equalizing hours, retention of substitutes, day-care nurseries (Box 8, Folder 26)
- Absences (Box 9, Folder 1)
- Accident insurance (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Campaign for Louis Goldman (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Campaign for Rudolf Holley (Pres. of NYC Council) (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Campaign for Vincent Kassenbrock (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Capital building projects, 1924-1947 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Cost of living material (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Democratic human relations (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Dewey, John (biographical material) (Box 9, Folder 9)
- End term clerical work (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Equalization of hours (vocational schools) (Box 9, Folder 11)
- Excessing of teachers (Box 9, Folder 12)
- Feinberg law - salaries (Box 9, Folder 13)
- HRLP Fund - Henry Linville Pension Fund (Box 9, Folder 14)
- In-Service courses (Box 9, Folder 15)
- Lincoln school (Box 9, Folder 16a)
- Lincoln school (Box 9, Folder 16b)
- Membership meetings (Box 9, Folder 17)
- Nation magazine ban (correspondence, et al.) (Box 9, Folder 18)
- Peace education: conference on, 1937 (Box 9, Folder 19)
- Publicity, clippings (Box 9, Folder 20)
- Quinn-Issacs Bill (Box 9, Folder 21)
- Questionnaire - sent out by Ray R. Peck (controversy over authorization) (Box 9, Folder 22)
- Questionnaire on rating system (Box 9, Folder 23)
- Criticism of Mayor LaGuardia (Box 9, Folder 24)
- Radio programs (Box 9, Folder 25)
- Recognition issue (by Board of Education) (Box 9, Folder 26)
- Special subjects teachers (Box 9, Folder 27)
- Speeches (on various topics) (Box 9, Folder 28)
- Selection of a superintendent (Box 9, Folder 29)
- Substitutes (Box 9, Folder 30)
- Supervisor members (Discussion on), 1952 (Box 9, Folder 31)
- Taxation and finance - information (Box 9, Folder 32)
- Teaching as a profession (Box 9, Folder 33)
- Teachers Guild - union finance (Box 9, Folder 34)
- Vocational schools (Box 9, Folder 35)
- Youthbuilders (Box 9, Folder 36)
- Publicity, Clippings (Box 9A, Folder 1)
- Questionnaire (Box 9A, Folder 2)
  Sent out by Ray R. Peck. Controversy over authorization
- Questionnaire on Rating System (Box 9A, Folder 3)
- Criticism of Mayor LaGuardia (Box 9A, Folder 4)
- "Recognition" Issue (Box 9A, Folder 5)
  By Board of Education
- Radio Programs (Box 9A, Folder 6)
- Special 'Subjects' Teachers (Box 9A, Folder 7)
- Speeches (Box 9A, Folder 8)
  On various topics
- Substitutes (Box 9A, Folder 9)
- Teachers' Guild: Union Finances (Box 9A, Folder 10)
- Selection of a Superintendent (Box 9A, Folder 11)
- Discussion on Supervisor Members, 1952 (Box 9A, Folder 12)
- Taxation and Finance Information [folder 1 of 2] (Box 9A, Folder 13)
- Taxation and Finance Information [folder 2 of 2] (Box 9A, Folder 14)
- Teaching as a Profession (Box 9A, Folder 15)
- Vocational Schools (Box 9A, Folder 16)
- Federal aid - the crisis in education (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Federal aid to education - volume #1 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Federal aid to education - volume #1 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Federal aid - general correspondence (Box 10, Folder 4)
- State aid to education (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Financial aid to education - state aid (Box 10, Folder 6)
- State aid - taxation and finance (Box 10, Folder 7a)
- State aid - taxation and finance (Box 10, Folder 7b)
- Correspondence with State Legislators (Re: state aid to education) (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Taxation for education - general, miscellaneous (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Committee on Religious instruction (Box 10, Folder 10)
- Teaching religious education (Box 10, Folder 11)
- Religion in the schools - Folder #1 (Box 10, Folder 12)
- Religion in the schools (Box 10, Folder 13)
- Religion in education (Box 10, Folder 14)